Guide to the Yale University Art, Architecture, and Art History Theses and Projects
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Art, architecture, and art history theses and projects, 1915-1996; Series I
  - Rittenberg Lawrence Saul. An Examination of my Artistic Growth. M.F.A. 8 p., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 411)
  - Robbin Anthony. My Painting M.F.A. 15 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 412)
  - Roberson Richard E. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 16 p., 1967 (Box 8, Folder 413)
  - Robie James Paul and Anthony E. Vander-perk. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 18 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 8, Folder 414)
  - Robinson Barbara S. El Greco. B.F.A. 12 p., 1940 (Box 8, Folder 415)
  - Rogoff Seymour Harold. General Technical Information Pertinent to Use of Poly Vinyl Acetate Emulsions. B.F.A. 36 p., 1952 (Box 8, Folder 416)
  - Rogoff Seymour Harold. Pictorial Conquest of Plastic Reality. M.F.A. 117 p., 1954 (Box 8, Folder 417)
  - Rosenberg L[eonard]. With Roots in the Old, a Step toward the New. B.F.A. 24 p., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 418)
  - Rosenblatt Adolph. Visual Aspects of Pre-Columbian Stamps. B.F.A. 117 p., 1956 (Box 8, Folder 419)
  - Rosenthal Stephen. Problems in Figure and Landscape Composition. B.F.A. 15 p., 1958 (Box 8, Folder 420)
  - Rothenberg Joan G. A Personal Essay on my work. M.F.A. 10 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 8, Folder 421)
  - Roy John A.[Jr.]. Optical Density. B.F.A. 34 p., [1957?] (Box 8, Folder 422)
  - Rubin Irwin. A Study of the Art of the Aborigines of Australia. B.F.A. 34 p., 1953 (Box 8, Folder 423)
  - Russom J[ohn] Michael. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 2 p. Slides., [1970?] (Box 8, Folder 424)
  - Rust Edwin C. Carl Mills - the Teacher. B.F.A. 12 p., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 425)
  - Sackstein, Robert [L.]. Toward a Unified Vision through More Effective Symbols. B.F.A. 15 p., 1952 (Box 8, Folder 426)
  - Sadowy Helen. Color as Used through a Transparent Medium. Glass. B.F.A. 9 p., 1958 (Box 8, Folder 427)
  - Safran Nora R. Plastic Media for Sculpture. B.F.A. 54 p., 1957 (Box 9, Folder 428)
  - Saldibar Peter S. The Parthenon. B.F.A. 8 p., 1931 (Box 9, Folder 429)
  - Sangiamo Albert. Line in Nature and Art: A Comparative Analysis.
    See: box 11, folder 545
  - Sangiamo Albert. The Outline in Drawing. M.F.A. 74 p., 1957 (Box 9, Folder 430)
  - Schactman Barry. The Figure in Relation to its Environment. B.F.A. 18 p., [1958?] (Box 9, Folder 431)
  - Schaefer Ernest R. Plaster Casting. B.F.A. 21 p., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 432)
  - Schappa Shirley. Fabric Printing. B.F.A. 10 p., 1958 (Box 9, Folder 433)
  - Schecter Robert. A Discussion of my Work: M.F.A. 9 p. Slides., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 434)
  - Schecter Susan Fortgan. Some Thoughts on my Painting. M.F.A. 17 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 435)
  - Schiebel Jeaniegray. Flemish Painting of the Fifteenth and Sixteenth Centuries. B.F.A. 10 p., 1939 (Box 9, Folder 436)
  - Schiffrin Herbert [S.]. [Six essays]. M.F.A. 12 p. Slides., [1968?] (Box 9, Folder 437)
  - Schnell John V. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 8 p. Slides, portfolio., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 438)
  - Schreiner Richard. Painting and I. [B.F.A.]. 5 p., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 439)
  - Schur Leona
    See: box 2, folder 63 box 2, folder 64
  - Schwartz Lyndell. Thesis on Sienese Painting. B.F.A. 9 p., 1933 (Box 9, Folder 440)
  - Seckel Paul B. The Art of Ingres and Delacroix: A Contribution toward an Analysis of their Work. M.F.A. 70 p., 1948 (Box 9, Folder 441)
  - Shapiro Julius. A Study of the Landscape Language of Van Gogh. B.F.A. 16 p., 1958 (Box 9, Folder 442)
  - Sheil Mary [R.]. Harmony in Painting. B.F.A. 10 p., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 443)
  - Shuman Morris. Casablanca. M.F.A. 5 p., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 444)
  - Silvercruys Suzanne
    See: box 4, folder 160
  - Silverman Harold Y. Design: Renaissance and Contemporary Times. B.F.A. 32 p., 1953 (Box 9, Folder 445)
  - Simard Stanley B. Propaganda and Painting B.F.A. 10 p., 1937 (Box 9, Folder 446)
  - Sitton John M. "Duccio di Bouninsegna": The Sienese. B.F.A. 9 p., 1929 (Box 9, Folder 447)
  - Sklar George John. Art as an Historical Document. B.F.A. 24 p., 1935 (Box 9, Folder 448)
  - Sklar George John. The Life of Claus Sluter. M.F.A. 33 p., 1937 (Box 9, Folder 449)
  - Slutzky Bob [Robert]. An Examination of "Actual Surface" in Oil Painting. B.F.A. 12 p., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 450)
  - Slutzky Robert. Art, Education, and Gestalt. M.F.A. 37 p., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 451)
  - Smith Jack Roberts. The Years of Duchamp. B.F.A. 17 p., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 452)
  - Smith Sally Lou. Modern Stained Glass as a Design Form. B.F.A. 26 p., 1953 (Box 9, Folder 453)
  - Snowden George H. Augustus St. Gaudens. B.F.A. 6 p., 1926 (Box 9, Folder 454)
  - Snyder Dennis Ralph. An Evaluation of my Painting Experience. M.F.A. 7 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 455)
  - Soule George Clifton. A Thesis on the Frescoe Murals in Dartmouth College by Jose Clemente Orozco. B.F.A. 15 p., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 456)
  - Spaenkuch August. Some Comments on Magazine Illustrations and Illustrators. B.F.A. 15 p., 1924 (Box 9, Folder 457)
  - Spaulding Warren [D.]. The Intuition Idea in Modern Painting. M.F.A. 50 p., 1950 (Box 9, Folder 458)
  - Speier Robert Walker. Plastic Space: Its Creation, Perception and Influence on the "de Stijl" Movement. B.F.A. 30 p., 1955 (Box 9, Folder 459)
  - Speier Robert Walker. Some Aspects of the Influence of Texture on Spatial Effect. M.F.A. 38 p., 1958 (Box 9, Folder 460)
  - Spillman John Edwin. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 15 p., 1966 (Box 9, Folder 461)
  - Stanczak Julian. Spatial Relationships on the Two Dimensional Surface. M.F.A. 55 p., 1956 (Box 9, Folder 462)
  - Stearns Priscilla. Paolo Veronese (Caliari): Character of Work and Comparison with Other Masters Venetian School. B.F.A. 14 p., 1936 (Box 9, Folder 463)
  - Steckel Jordan. A Confusion in Concepts. B.F.A. 12 p., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 464)
  - Steever Edgar Z. [IV]. Considerations of South Mayan Reliefs. B.F.A. 20 p., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 465)
  - Steever Edgar Z.IV. Mayan Art: Sculptural Developments at Piedras Negras. M.F.A. 83 p., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 466)
  - Sterling Elizabeth Parks. The Use of Plastics for Color Transparencies. B.F.A. 12 p., 1958 (Box 9, Folder 467)
  - Sternberg Charlotte [J.]. Concerning the General Characteristics of Chinese Painting up till the End of the T"ang" Dynasty. B.F.A. 16 p., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 468)
  - Stevenson Mrs. Edward F.
  - Stewart Jack T. Jr. Pigments and the Medium B.F.A. 44 p., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 469)
  - Stokes, Franklyn Haven. Fra Angelico B.F.A. 27 p., 1939 (Box 9, Folder 470)
  - Haven R[ichard] Leonard Jr. [Untitled] M.F.A. 15 p. Slides., [1969?] (Box 9, Folder 471)
  - Stone Ernest Lynn. Botticelli, Renaissance Italian. B.F.A. 20 p., 1936 (Box 9, Folder 472)
  - Stone Mary Elizabeth. Angelica Kauffmann. B.F.A. 14 p., 1943 (Box 9, Folder 473)
  - Swenson Rod[eric] B. Flashworks and Fleck Theory M.F.A., 47 p., [1969?] (Box 9, Folder 474)
  - Swift Philip W. Thoughts on a Museum Education B.F.A. 13 p., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 475)
  - Swift Philip W. Some Aspects of Object Presentation M.F.A. 55 p., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 476)
  - Swirnoff Lois [C.]. A Study of Masaccio's Form B.F.A. 41 p., 1953 (Box 9, Folder 477)
  - Swirnoff Lois [C.]. Spatial Aspects of Color M.F.A. 42 p., 1956 (Box 9, Folder 478)
  - Tanner Sister Mary Bartholomew O. P. Creation Themes and Other Related Works. M.F.A. 11 p. Slides., 1963 (Box 9, Folder 479)
  - Tauss Charles [J.]. Some Aspects of Early Flemish Paintings and Methods. B.F.A. 22 p., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 480)
  - Tauss Charles [J.]. The Church of Christ in Chora (Karieh Djami): Notes on the Parecclesion. M.F.A. 63 p., 1955 (Box 9, Folder 481)
  - Tedeschi Paul V. Giovanni of Fiesole (Fra Angelico). B.F.A. 12 p., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 482)
  - Tedeschi Paul V. Comparison of the Stylistic Elements in the Landscape Art of Early china for a Possible Redating of the Archer and the Mountain Scene in the Admonitions Scroll. M.F.A. 48 p., 1949 (Box 9, Folder 483)
  - Tenenbaum Gary Richard. An Essay on Works Executed at Yale University. M.F.A. 16 p. Portfolio., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 484)
  - Thompson George William. An Iconographical Study. B.F.A. 28 p., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 485)
  - Thoms Margaret Alison. Albert Pinkham Ryder. B.F.A. 10 p., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 486)
  - Thomsen Frederick C. The Centaur as Interpreted in Sculpture throughout the Periods. B.F.A. 25 p., 1932 (Box 9, Folder 487)
  - Thorne Gordon Grand. Some Thoughts on Myself as an Artist, and the Things I Create, and Call Art. M.F.A. 7 p., [1966?] (Box 10, Folder 488)
  - Thorne Thomas. The Technical Methods of Peter Paul Rubens, as Observed in the Painting, Venus and Adonis; in the Metropolitan Museum - New York. B.F.A. 16 p., 1940 (Box 10, Folder 489)
  - Tobey Alton S. An Introduction to the History and Appreciation of Persian Painting. [B.F.A.] 18 p., 1937 (Box 10, Folder 490)
  - Tobey Alton [s.]. A Comparison of Two Works of Art as an Expression of their Respective Cultures. M.F.A. [1948]. 85 p., 1947 (Box 10, Folder 491)
  - Tompkins Alan. On the Development of Drawing from Conventionalism to Naturalism during the Italian Renaissance. B.F.A. 17 p., 1933 (Box 10, Folder 492)
  - Trussell Philip R. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 12 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 493)
  - Trussell Ruth R. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 13 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 494)
  - Tulk Alfred James. The Ultimate Aim of Art. B.F.A. 11 p., 1923 (Box 10, Folder 495)
    See: box 8, folder 414
  - Tulk Duncan C. Contemporary Murals. B.F.A. 26 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 496)
  - Valier Biron Frank. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 9 p. Slides., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 497)
  - Vanderperk Anthony Evert
  - Van Duzer Clarence E. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 53 p., 1947 (Box 10, Folder 498)
  - Van Dyk, James. The Book of Isaiah. B.F.A. 25 p., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 499)
  - Van Esselstyn, Mari-Louise. The X-ray as a Means of Scientific Research in the Field of Painting. B.F.A. 14 p., 1944 (Box 10, Folder 500)
  - Varsh Vincent J. Persian Miniature Painting Bihzad's Contribution. B.F.A. 16 p., 1948 (Box 10, Folder 501)
  - Vetos Spiro G. Collaboration. M.F.A. 95 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 502)
  - Voichysonk Bernard Francis. Color Etching. B.F.A. 12 p., 1958 (Box 10, Folder 503)
  - Wade Jean Elizabeth. Fra Angelico. B.F.A. 20 p, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 504)
  - Walker Clare [V.]. Jehan Foucquet: French Painter and Manuscript Illuminator. B.F.A. 20 p., 1941 (Box 10, Folder 505)
  - Walker Herbert Brooks. Modalloy: A Contribution to Sculpture. B.F.A. 15 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 506)
  - Waller Richard. The Thesis Statement. M.F.A. 17 p., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 507)
  - Walther Elsbeth C. National Art Appreciation. B.F.A. 14 p., 1934 (Box 10, Folder 508)
  - Watson Hubert C. The Art of Illumination. B.F.A. 12 p, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 509)
  - Watson Natalie Comstock. Piero Della Francesca. B.F.A. 15 p, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 510)
  - Waugh Douglas V. The History of Map-Making. B.F.A. 23 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 511)
  - Weatherbee, Francis E. The Horse in Art. B.F.A. 7 p., 1931 (Box 10, Folder 512)
  - Weinberg Elbert. The Fountain. [M.F.A.] 48 p, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 513)
    See also: box 8, folder 19
  - Weishar Joseph. Willem de Kooning. B.F.A. 40 p., 1954 (Box 10, Folder 514)
  - Welles Halsted Sutherland. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 5 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 515)
  - Wells Lynette Burton. Sculpture as the Materialization of Space. M.F.A. 20 p. Portfolio., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 516)
  - Wendell Raymond John. Non-Objective Painting. M.F.A. 104 p., 1950 (Box 10, Folder 517)
  - Wiener Samuel G. Jr. Repetition. B.F.A. 14 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 518)
  - Williams William Thomas Jr. "Houdini's Manual for the Working Artist" or "You too can Use Sherman Williams Kem Hi-Gloss Enamel" or "I Never for Realised it Paid to Shop Auto Insurance:" M.F.A. 13 p., 1968 (Box 10, Folder 519)
  - Williams Winslow. Form Description in Painting. B.F.A. 15 p., 1941 (Box 10, Folder 520)
  - Wilson Mark. [Untitled] M.F.A. 5 p. Slides., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 521)
  - Wilson William W. S. Contemporary Portrait Painting: A Critique. B.F.A. 8 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 522)
  - Wolsky Alan M. The Relationship of Art to Society. B.F.A. 21 p., 1954 (Box 10, Folder 523)
  - Wonderlick Alfred Leon. [Untitled portfolio]. M.F.A. 33 p., 1965 (Box 10, Folder 524)
  - Wondriska. William Allen. A Study of the Bauhaus …and the Conditions Influencing its Existance [sic] and Development. B.F.A. 38 p., 1954 (Box 10, Folder 525)
  - Wright G[uier] Scott, Jr.
    See: box 2, folder 80
  - Wright Shirley Gregory (Mrs. Guier Scott Jr.). Approaches to Landscape Water color Painting. B.F.A. 22 p., 1952 (Box 10, Folder 526)
  - Yanosik Ruth E. The Doctrine, Painters. B.F.A. 15 p., 1949 (Box 10, Folder 527)
  - Yrizarry John Cameron. The Horse in Twentieth Century Art. B.F.A. 23 p., 1954 (Box 10, Folder 528)
  - Yue John Kia. Artist's Statement. M.F.A. 6 p. Slides., 1970 (Box 10, Folder 529)
  - Yura Stephen. The Russian Ikon: Past and Present. B.F.A. 17 p., 1953 (Box 10, Folder 530)
  - Zaborowski Dennis. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 12 p. Slides., 1968 (Box 10, Folder 531)
  - Zallinger Jean Day (Mrs. Rudolph F.). Andrea Mantegna. B.F.A. 11 p., 1942 (Box 10, Folder 532)
  - Zallinger Rudolph F. Modes of Drawing. B.F.A. 13 p., 1942 (Box 10, Folder 533)
  - Zaretsky Sol. Design Education. B.F.A. 14 p., 1952 (Box 10, Folder 534)
  - Zelanski Paul. White - Long Loop Uncut, Short Loop Cut. B.F.A. 37 p., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 535)
  - Ziemann Richard Claude. Stained Glass Experiments. B.F.A. 15 p., 1956 (Box 10, Folder 536)
  - Zimmermann R[obert] W. The Handwriting of Rubens: Thesis in white. B.F.A. 11 p., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 537)
  - Zingale Michael. The Spiritual as Revealed Meaning. M.F.A. 5 p. Slides, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 538)
  - Zorthian Jirayr H. Armenian Art and its Influences. B.F.A. 20 p., 1936 (Box 10, Folder 539)
  - Zuppardi Charles G. [Untitled]. M.F.A. 8 p. Slides., 1969 (Box 10, Folder 540)
  - Milici Salvatore M. American Architectural Sculpture. B.F.A. 20 p., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 541)
  - Unidentified. The Vision After the Sermon. M.F.A. 77 p., 1962 (Box 10, Folder 542)
  - Bailey William H. Some Methods of Articulating Volume and Space in Drawing. M.F.A. 53 p., 1957 (Box 11, Folder 543)
  - Forrest Rita Virginia. Design Perception at the Secondary Level. B.F.A. 40 p., 1957 (Box 11, Folder 544)
  - Sangiamo, Albert. Line in Nature and Art: A Comparative Analysis. B.F.A. 42 p., 1955 (Box 11, Folder 545)
- Master's class projects, 1953-1967; Series II
  - Architecture, Master's Class, Fall 1966 Edited transcript from tape recording
    - Seminar #1, 1966 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Seminar #2, 1966 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Post Mortem, 1966 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Seminar #3, 1966 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Seminar #4, 1966 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Seminar #5, 1966 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Seminar #6, 1966 December 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Seminar #7, 1967 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Seminar #8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Review, 1967 January (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Art and Architecture, Master's Class, 1953-1966
    - Abbott, J. Carl (2), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Alcorn, James, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Anderson, John, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Baggley, Richard H., 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Beeby, Thomas (Team), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Birkby, N. Phyllis, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bobrow, Philip David, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Briscoe, Barrie, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Buchanan, George, 1960-1961, 1961-1962
      See: box 1, folders 1-2
    - Buchanan, Marvin, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Busselle, Samuel, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Campbell, Richard (3), 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Carroll, Richard (2), 1964-1965, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Chermayeff, Serge and Tzonis, Alexander, 1967
    - Chisholm, John, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Conrad, Peter S., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cooper, Alexander, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cox, W., 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Crosby, William, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Damilo, Joan, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - David, T. L., 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Digerud, et al, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Dobbins, Michael, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Edwards, Jared, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Engberg, Charles M., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Faesy, Robert, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Fix, David, 1959-1960, 1960-1961
      See: box 1, folders 3-4
    - Foster, Norman, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Foster, Norman and Rogers, Richard, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Galston, John W., 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Glass, Christopher (2), 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gluck, Peter L., 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Golz, Lawrence, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Goody, Marvin E., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gorman, Robert (3), 1962-1963, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      See: box 9, folder 23
    - Gottschalk, Peter M., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gottschalk, Peter M. and Morton, David C., 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gross, Frank, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Guthrie, R. Larason, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gwathmey, Charles (3), 1960-1961, 1961-1962
      See: box 1, folders 5-7
    - Hadley, Glen, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Hagenah, Charles (3), 1961-1962, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hansen, Margaret (2), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Harter, Michael, 1961
      See: box 1, folder 8
    - Harvey, Joshua, 1961-1962
    - Hatami, M., 1960-1961
      See: box 1, folder 9
    - Hersey, William, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Heyne, Pamela, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hipp, Gail, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Hockaday, Peter, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hoppner, Peter, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Hosford, Charles D. (3), 1961-1962, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Houston, Andre F., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Ide, Kazu, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Islam, M., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Jacobs, Lawrence R., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Johnson, Edward T., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Kaji, et al, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Kimura, Seinosuke (2), 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Kinoshita, Gene, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Kroeger, Keith, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lange, Neil A. de H. (3), 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lee, John, 1961, 1961-1962
      See: box 1, folders 10-11
    - Leiding, Gelinda, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Liacas, Walter (2), 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Lo, Ching-Ning, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Lo, Ching-Ning and David B. Ryan, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - MacLean, Charles, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Marks, Robert, 1961, 1961-1962, 1962-1963
      See: box 1, folders 12-14
    - Metz, Donald A. (4), 1962-1963, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Michael, Gary L. (2), 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Miller, Bruce K. (3), 1963-1964, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Miller, Robert M., 1962-1963, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Mitsui, Mamoru, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Mittelstadt, Robert J., 1961-1962, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Moore, B., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Moore, Bill, 1966? (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Morton, David C., 1963-1964, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Nagy, Ernest, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Nakasuji, Osamu (2), 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Naladalakar, Sudha, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Natkin, Kenneth R., 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Noga, Yuji, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Ormsby, Charles, 1961
      See: box 1, folder 15
    - Paranjpe, Subhash (2), 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Pearce, John I., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Peterson, Steen, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Pierce, Gifford, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Pittarelli, Emilio (4), 1963-1964, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Pleuthner, Charles M.(3), 1962-1963, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Purves, Alexander, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Robertson, J., 1959-1960
      see: box 1, folder 16
    - Roth, David, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Roy, Charles, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Ryan, David B., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - St. Martin, John W., 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Sarli, Irini, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Scheyhing, Ernest, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Scutt, D. (3), 1959-1960, 1961
      See: box 1, folders 17-19
    - Sellers, David E. (3), 1961-1962, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Sheriff, Wallace (4), 1960-1961, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Simpson, Barry, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Smith III, W. Mason, 1962-1963, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Stern, Robert A. M., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Sze, Chiu-Ming (2), 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Thorbeck, Duane (3), 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Tigerman, Stanley, 1959-1960, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Todd, Leonard M. (2), 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Tso, Roland, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Tzonis, Alexander, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Tzonis, A., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Walker, Lester, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Watson, Donald, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Weintraub, Miles, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Whitaker, Craig, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Wight, David, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Wu, Ming, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Yamashita, Tsukasa, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Yanik, John (2), 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Yegul, Fikret, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Yokota, Takemi, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Zimmerman, Robert (2), 1961-1962, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Theses and research papers, 1934, 1943-1977; Series III
  - Adelberg, Marion. Zen Influence in Japanese Painting: A Study in Iconography. M.A. (HA) 123 p., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Agee, William C.,. Raymond Duchamp-Villon (1876-1918) Vol. I&II. M.A. (HA) 126 p., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Ahmed, Najmuddin,. Village India. M.C.P. 65 p., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Anderson, John,. U-Bag, The Urban Renewal Game for the Whole. M. Arch. 38 p., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Averill, Louise. The Architectural Element in Romanesque Painting: A Study of French Murals in the Loire Region. M.A. 49 p., undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bandelin, Susan Ball. André Derain's Figural Paintings and Sculpture, 1905-1910: A Re-examination. Ph.D. 133 p., undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bayard, Jane H. La Bella Mano: Dante Gabriel Rosetti and the Tradition of the Erotic Altarpiece. M.A. (HA) 78 p., 1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bemis, Margaret. Planning Methodology for the Small, Northeastern Town. Essay: C.P., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Benedikt, Michael L. The Information Field: A Theoretical and Empirical Approach to the Distribution and Transfer of Information in the Physical Environment. M.E.D. 165 p., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Bershen, Wanda. The Films of Maya Deren Dept. Paper. 98 p., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Betchaku, Yasuko. Three Undated Sets of "The Eight Views of the Hsiao and Hsiang" by Ike no Taiga (1723-1776). M.A. (HA) 96 p., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Birnholz, Alan C. El Lissitzky: Proun. Vol. I & II. Dept. Paper. (HA) 139 p., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - Blau, Eve Marion. Ruskinian Gothic: The Architecture of Deane and Woodward 1852-1861. Vol. I & II. M.A. (HA) 197 p., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Blum, Pamela Z. A Study of the Thirteenth-Century Sculptures in the Spandrels of the Blind Arcade of the Salisbury Cathedral Chapter-house. Vol. I. M.A. (HA) [Vol. II missing] Vol II AVALIABLE ON FILM HM 207, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Bohan, P.J. The Early Colonial Architecture of Farmington, Connecticut. M.A. (HA) 140 p., 1957 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)